<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on R4J's Personal Site</title><link>https://rajsimmanravi.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on R4J's Personal Site</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 23:36:10 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajsimmanravi.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Better Late Than Never: My First Open Source Contribution</title><link>https://rajsimmanravi.github.io/posts/ooni-first-pr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 07:40:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rajsimmanravi.github.io/posts/ooni-first-pr/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently made my first open-source contribution by fixing a bug in the OONI Backend project. What started as browsing &amp;ldquo;good first issue&amp;rdquo; labels turned into an exciting journey through internet censorship detection, load balancing algorithms, and Docker debugging. With Claude Code as my pair programming partner, I navigated unfamiliar code and successfully submitted &lt;a href="https://github.com/ooni/backend/pull/1048"&gt;PR #1048&lt;/a&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="why-i-finally-decided-to-contribute"&gt;Why I Finally Decided to Contribute&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s my honest truth: I’ve been a software engineer for over five years, using numerous open-source tools daily, and I’ve never contributed back. Not once. I felt guilty about it, especially when I saw projects like ingress-nginx struggle to find maintainers and eventually get deprecated. I used that tool constantly, knew how valuable it was to the Kubernetes community, and yet I never helped.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Datadog vs Grafana Dashboards</title><link>https://rajsimmanravi.github.io/posts/datadog/datadog-grafana/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 12:45:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rajsimmanravi.github.io/posts/datadog/datadog-grafana/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When comparing dashboards between Datadog and Grafana, we often find discrepancies between them. Even though both Datadog and Grafana scrape metrics from the same source, we see vastly differing visualizations and we often wonder which has a better accuracy compared to the source of truth. In this blog post, we explore the discrepancies between Grafana and DataDog dashboards and how we can resolve/understand them. We begin by giving a brief overview on the data (or metrics) being collected.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Uncovering Cryptojacking/Phishing At University of Toronto</title><link>https://rajsimmanravi.github.io/posts/crytojacking/cryptojacking-phishing-savi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 17:50:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://rajsimmanravi.github.io/posts/crytojacking/cryptojacking-phishing-savi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;During my Masters work at University of Toronto (U of T), my research group was responsible for building and maintaining an OpenStack-based Cloud infrastructure such that other research teams from various universities can utilize this Cloud platform. One of the interesting things I worked on was the security aspects of the platform; mainly playing with installing Fail2ban, OSSEC and investigating security threats/issues on the platform. There was one instance we got an alert from the main U of T Security team that there was a backdoor Command-and-Control traffic running on a VM that was on our platform. The VM was hosting a Wordpress-based web-server. This blog is about how I investigated this issue on our platform.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>